AURELIE JOSSERAND

Front-End Software Engineer

Front-end developer and multidisciplinary designer currently based in Washington D.C.

Over ten years of experience in delivering products for companies, businesses and government entities around the globe with a focus on design, usability, accessibility and inclusivity.

CONTACT

josserand.n.aurelie@gmail.com (405) 503-7341

Pronouns: She / They

TOOLBOX

HTML5 CSS JavaScript React Github

Figma

Google Workspace Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Indesign Adobe Premiere Pro

3DSMAX Lumion Sketchup Revit Dynamo AutoCAD

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent French - Native Spanish - Beginner

OTHER QUALIFICATIONS

Registered Architect EDAC Accredited LEED Accredited LEED Accredited BD+C

Green Card Holder

EXPERIENCE

Codecademy - Front End Engineer Track

Winter 2021 to Present

SmithGroup, Washington, District of Columbia

2015 to present - Project Architect

- Leads system coordination on large scale projects involving multi-disciplinary teams of engineers and designers.
- Involved in all project phases from project pursuits to construction administration.
- Promotes the company brand through online and in person community activities and organization involvement.

Miles Associates, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

2012 to 2015 - Project Coordinator

- Developed the company Website Design using Squarespace CMS.
- Led 3D visualizations efforts.
- Assisted project teams on construction documentation and project pursuits.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Smithgroup - Technology in Practice Group

Summer 2017 to present - Digital Delivery Champion

Identifies and Implements automation processes and BIM standards.

Academy of Architecture for Health

2017 to 2020 - FTP & Logistics Lead Member

EDUCATION

University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK

Spring 2011 to Summer 2012

Bachelor of Architecture, NAAB Professional Degree

Ecole Nationale Superieure d'Architecture, France

Fall 2007 to Fall 2010

Bachelor of Architecture, Non-Professional Degree

AWARD

Summer Leadership Summit - Next Generation Scholar Recipient

Summer Leadership Summit 2017